<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Power Platform on Kamil Rithaler</title>
    <link>https://rithala.github.io/tags/power-platform/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Power Platform on Kamil Rithaler</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://rithala.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://rithala.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 22:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rithala.github.io/tags/power-platform/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Automate deployments of custom Power Platform connectors</title>
      <link>https://rithala.github.io/posts/automate-deployments-of-custom-power-platform-connectors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 22:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rithala.github.io/posts/automate-deployments-of-custom-power-platform-connectors/</guid>
      <description>Power Platform custom connectors enable using your API in Power Apps or Power Automate flows. When the API which you plan to integrate with your app is a stable and finished product, then creating a custom connector is a one-time task to do. However, when the API is a part of a developed solution or is under active development then keeping the connector in sync with the API is a cumbersome task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to aggregate (SUM, AVG, COUNT etc.) SharePoint list items&#39; data efficient in Power Automate</title>
      <link>https://rithala.github.io/posts/sharepoint-list-items-aggregations-in-power-automate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 14:33:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rithala.github.io/posts/sharepoint-list-items-aggregations-in-power-automate/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s assume you need to summarize the sales data per salesman and prepare a monthly report that will be sent to the manager.
How can you do this in Power Automate? The first thing that may come to your mind is to use SharePoint&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Get Items&amp;rdquo; action to get all list items for the desired time frame and then calculate the sums yourself in the &amp;ldquo;Apply to each&amp;rdquo; loop. It may work for a small list but it will fail when we get to a larger number of items.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power Automate Chrome Extension</title>
      <link>https://rithala.github.io/posts/power-automate-chrome-extension/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 14:33:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rithala.github.io/posts/power-automate-chrome-extension/</guid>
      <description>I bet every PowerAutomate consultant wonders if there is an easy way to replace all SharePoint site URLs or variables names in a flow definition 🤔 I could not find the answer, so I built this small (my first😊) Chrome/Edge extension allowing editing a flow as JSON in a web version of VS Code. Please, share this with your colleagues and feedback is much appreciated 😉
Link to GitHub
Link to the Chrome Web Store</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
